<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marketing on Data Automation</title>
    <link>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/categories/marketing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marketing on Data Automation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 20:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/categories/marketing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do you use tag managers for everything?</title>
      <link>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/voce-usa-gerenciadores-de-tags-para-tudo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/voce-usa-gerenciadores-de-tags-para-tudo/</guid>
      <description>Tag managers are convenient for managing scripts and avoiding conflicts between marketing and development teams. All snippets of code that are injected on a page are managed from the same place and code maintenance is easier. Very good! Now, what happens when you receive a visitor on your site that is using an ad blocker?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People behind personas</title>
      <link>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/as-pessoas-por-tras-das-personas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/as-pessoas-por-tras-das-personas/</guid>
      <description>Customers today are very different from those from previous decades. Throughout this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll get to know some important milestones that changed customer behavior to understand how to conquer and retain customers that are looking for much more than quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The day that marketing derailed</title>
      <link>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/o-dia-em-que-o-marketing-saiu-dos-trilhos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 19:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/o-dia-em-que-o-marketing-saiu-dos-trilhos/</guid>
      <description>Marketing departments were transformed as internet got popular and new consumer channels and new technologies arose. Today it is possible to calculate the return on investment for each cent invested, but this level of power was achieved without first debating on its ethical implications. Are we using digital marketing the right way to deliver value to people?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic thank you pages using RD Station</title>
      <link>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/paginas-de-agradecimento-dinamicas-no-rd-station/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 21:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/paginas-de-agradecimento-dinamicas-no-rd-station/</guid>
      <description>How to display dynamic content on thank you pages for converted leads using RD Station?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory research for modeling personas</title>
      <link>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/fundamentos-da-pesquisa-exploratoria/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 21:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/fundamentos-da-pesquisa-exploratoria/</guid>
      <description>Personas are much used as guidance for developing products and services that people want. Defining personas help guide not only the direction of the product, but also processes related to customer satisfaction such as communication and support. Mapping personas, though, require research. How to use research methods to map the organization&amp;rsquo;s personas?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific experiments for businesses</title>
      <link>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/experimentacao-no-mundo-dos-negocios/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 09:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/experimentacao-no-mundo-dos-negocios/</guid>
      <description>At academies, knowledge is obtained when executing tests on laboratories, controlled environments that allow for easily identification of causes and effects. Resulting knowledge is trustworthy and the process by which was obtained is both verifiable and replicable. It is possible to transpose knowledge production methods used in the academy to business environments to produce knowledge with the same level of quality to drive decisions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SEO &#43; CRO: end to end optimization</title>
      <link>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/seo-e-cro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 08:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/seo-e-cro/</guid>
      <description>Search engines like Google go well beyond keywords in order to show search results. Many techniques are employed to match the right results to the right person at the right time. At the corporate marketing end, SEO professionals work to make their results reach the top of search pages, resulting in more website visits. What happens after that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The optimization aspect of CRO</title>
      <link>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/a-parte-de-otimizacao-em-cro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 06:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/a-parte-de-otimizacao-em-cro/</guid>
      <description>As best as it can be any given purchase experience, there is always something to improve. This is, at least, one of the premises of those who work with CRO, or Conversion Rate Optimization. Find out what is CRO and how to use conversion optimization techniques to find growth opportunities within digital products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth Value</title>
      <link>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/growth-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 20:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.automacaodedados.com.br/en/stories/growth-value/</guid>
      <description>What is Growth Value?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
